Guide to the Edie Windsor and Thea Spyer Papers MSS.642
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series I. Personal, 1888-2023; 1950-2000; 25 Linear Feet in 39 manuscript boxes, 2 small flat boxes, 4 oversize flat boxes, and 1 flat-file folder; 472.91 Megabytes in 441 computer files
  - Subseries I.C. Household, 1953-2017; 12.80 Linear Feet in 15 manuscript boxes, 4 oversized flat boxes, and 1 flat-file folder.; 472.91 Megabytes in 441 computer files
    - Edie and Thea Attending and Hosting Parties Images, 1969-2009
      - Photographs, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 62, Folder 3)
      - Photographs, 1974 (Box 62, Folder 4)
      - Photographs, circa 1980s (Box 62, Folder 37)
      - Photographs, circa 1980s-1990s (Box 62, Folder 5)
      - Photographs, circa mid-1980s - 1990s (Box 62, Folder 36)
      - Slide Images, September 1986 (Box 62, Folder 35)
      - Photographs, circa 2000-2009 (Box 62, Folder 6)
    - Edie and Thea Posing and Portrait Images, 1969-2009
      - Photograph, September 14, 1969 (Box 62, Folder 8)
      - Photographs and Contact Sheet, January 7, 1974 (Box 62, Folder 9)
      - Photographs, 1975 (Box 62, Folder 7)
      - Slide Images, 1984 (Box 62, Folder 10)
      - Photographs, March 1986 (Box 62, Folder 11)
      - Photographs, 1994 (Box 62, Folder 12)
      - Digital Images by Neville Elder, May 29, 2007; FA_MSS_642_ER_21
      - Photographs, circa 2000-2009 (Box 62, Folder 13)
      - Photographs of Wheelchair Dancing, circa 2007-2009 (Box 62, Folder 14)
    - Edie and Thea Posing at The Met Cloisters, and Restaurant Photographs and Slides, December 1965 (Box 62, Folder 1)
    - Edie Birthday Photographs and Slides, June 1967 (Box 62, Folder 15)
    - Edie Birthday Slide Images, June 1984 (Box 62, Folder 16)
    - Edie Building a Harpsichord, Thea On Couch, and Party -- Photographs and Negatives, 1965-1966 (Box 62, Folder 17)
    - Edie Pre- and Post-Surgery -- Photographs and Slides, November 1970 (Box 62, Folder 18)
    - Estates and Trusts -- Thea's Wills, Correspondence, Health/Legal Directives, and Related Documents, 1987-2004 (Box 26, Folder 7-12)
    - Estates and Trusts -- Correspondence, Notes, 2004; FA_MSS_642_ER_33
    - Estates and Trusts -- WINSPY LLC Partnership Documents, 2006; FA_MSS_642_ER_34
    - Estates and Trusts -- Thea's Death Letters Testamentary, Estate Probate Proceedings, Closing Thea's Practice, 2009-2010
      - Paper (Box 26, Folder 13-17)
      - Digital Files, FA_MSS_642_ER_35
    - Estates and Trusts -- Financial Exhibits for Thea's Estate, 2009-2010 (Box 26, Folder 18)
    - Estates and Trusts -- Financial Analysis and Tax Returns and Resubmissions, 2009-2013 (Box 27, Folder 1-7)
    - Friend Participating in the International Games for the Disabled Summer Olympics Photographs, 1984 (Box 62, Folder 19)
    - Friends, Edie, and Thea Photographs, May 1987 (Box 62, Folder 20)
    - Friends, Edie, and Thea Photographs, 1993, April-May 1998 (Box 62, Folder 21-22, 33)
    - Friends, Family, Edie, and Thea Photographs, 2004, circa 2005-2009 (Box 62, Folder 23)
    - Friends Dev and Shelly Photographs, circa 2000-2017 (Box 62, Folder 24)
    - Halloween with Edie and Thea Dressed as Bride and Groom Photographs and Negatives, October 1981 (Box 62, Folder 25)
    - Halloween Party at Edie and Thea Apartment Photographs, October 1986 (Box 62, Folder 26)
    - Health History and Documentation (1977-2008) for Thea (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Home Healthcare-Related, 1986-2008
      - Lifts and Other Related Assistance Booklets, Advertisements for Home Healthcare Aids (Box 27, Folder 9, Box 28, Folder 1-2)
      - Photographs of Accessible Bedroom and Bathroom, Wheelchair Cushions (Box 62, Folder 27)
      - Home Health Aid Duty Lists, FA_MSS_642_ER_36
    - Household Expenses and Investment Notes, 1979, 2007, undated (Box 28, Folder 3-4)
    - Investments Reports, 1971, 1982, 1997 (Box 28, Folder 5, Box 72, Folder 8)
    - Jon Rieder (Edie Nephew) Wedding Photographs, March 1981 (Box 62, Folder 28)
    - Jury Duty-Related Documents, 1988-2007 (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Mary Mulligan Memorial Photographs, July 1985 (Box 62, Folder 29)
    - Memorial Day Weekend at Teddie and Elaine's Photographs, May 29, 1993 (Box 62, Folder 30)
    - MJ Birthday Party Slide Images, Summer 1984 (Box 62, Folder 31)
    - "Mrs. Fordham's" Hamptons Summer Rental House Weekends, and Edie's Engagement Pin -- Photographs and Slides, Summer 1966-January 1967 (Box 62, Folder 32)
    - National MS Society New York Chapter Event Material, 1998 (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - New Year's Eve Party, 1991-1992
      - Planning Notes (Box 28, Folder 8)
      - Photographs and Negatives (Box 62, Folder 34)
    - Notebooks and Notes -- Party Planning, circa 1970s (Box 57, Folder 11)
    - Notebooks and Notes -- Thea Health Journal, Financial Notes, House Renovation To-Do Lists, circa 1980s-2009 (Box 28, Folder 9-11)
    - Notebooks and Notes -- Thea's Memorial Service Planning, Financial Analysis Notes, 2008-2010 (Box 28, Folder 12)
    - Notebooks and Notes -- Health Journal, Renovations, undated (Box 28, Folder 13-16)
    - Photograph Album (Deconstructed) -- Edie and Thea with Friends, Family, on the Beach, 1964-1965 (Box 63, Folder 1)
    - Photograph Album (Deconstructed) -- Parties, Trips, and Wall of Edie's Wigs, August 1971 - March 1972 (Box 63, Folder 2)
    - Photograph Album (Deconstructed) -- Party for FAH-801 Cut-Off 3-month Reunion Group, October 19, 1973 (Box 63, Folder 3)
    - Photograph Album (Deconstructed) and Negatives -- Edie, Thea, and Friend Posing in Different Outfits, 1973 (Box 63, Folder 4)
    - Photograph Album (Deconstructed) -- Pool Party at Corinne's, Tuckahoe Lane House Exteriors, Nudes of Thea and Edie, 1973-1974 (Box 63, Folder 5)
    - Photograph Album (Deconstructed) and Negatives -- Family Events, Visitors, Thea, Edie, and Trips to Family and Friends, 1981-1983 (Box 63, Folder 6)
    - Photograph Album -- Portraits of Edie, Backyard at Tuckahoe Lane House, 1992, 1999 (Box 63, Folder 7)
    - Proof for Bruce Weber "All-American Series" Booklet on Edie and Thea: "Let Us Live, Let Us Love", 2013 (Box 72, Folder 10)
    - Rosh Hashanah and Thea's 50th Birthday Slide Images, October 1981 (Box 63, Folder 8)
    - Savings Account Register / Journal, 1998-2000 (Box 28, Folder 17)
    - Slide Image Descriptions and Lists Removed from Storage Containers, 1966-1981 (Box 57, Folder 13)
    - Softball Game with Edie, Thea, and Friends, and Thea Golfing Photographs, circa 1970s (Box 63, Folder 9)
    - Song Lyrics for A Circle of Diamonds and I Could Fall in Love by Dan Martin and Michael Bello, 2015 (Box 28, Folder 18-19)
    - Thanksgiving with Friends Photographs, circa 1980s (Box 63, Folder 10)
    - Thanksgiving with Dolly (Edie Sister) and Family Slide Images, November 1980 (Box 63, Folder 11)
    - Thanksgiving with Friends Slide Images, November 1986 (Box 63, Folder 12)
    - Thanksgiving with Friend Photographs, November 1994 (Box 63, Folder 13)
    - Thanksgiving Digital Images, 2004; FA_MSS_642_ER_37
    - "Thea and Edie, A Love Story. 1965 until Death Do Us Part" Photograph Booklet, circa 2007 (Box 63, Folder 14)
    - Thea Medical-Related Notes and Spreadsheets, 2003-2008; FA_MSS_642_ER_38
    - Thea Memorial Planning and Bereavement Reply Cards, 2009 (Box 29, Folder 1, Box 72, Folder 9)
    - Thea in Stand-Up Wheelchair Photographs, March 30, 1991 (Box 63, Folder 15)
    - Thea in Wheelchair Attending Abilities Expo Photographs, circa 1990s-2000s (Box 63, Folder 16)
    - Travel -- Suriname, South America, December 1965 - January 1966
      - Guide Book, Press Clippings, Slide Storage Box Description (Box 29, Folder 2)
      - Paramaribo and Jungle Village Slide Images (Box 63, Folder 17-19, Box 64, Folder 1-2)
    - Travel -- Image Lists from Trips from 1965 to 1981, circa 1980s (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Travel -- St. Thomas, Pacific Northwest, and Hambletonian Spa Slide Images, 1968 (Box 64, Folder 3)
    - Travel -- St. Thomas Slide Images, January 1969 (Box 64, Folder 4)
    - Travel -- Stoneybrook Slide Images, January 1969 (Box 64, Folder 5)
    - Travel -- Europe and Tangier Trip Photographs and Slide Images, June 1969 (Box 64, Folder 6)
    - Travel -- Saba Slide Images, January 1972 (Box 64, Folder 7)
    - Travel -- France and Italy Slide Images, September/October 1972 (Box 64, Folder 8)
    - Travel -- Grenada Slide Images, January 1973 (Box 64, Folder 9)
    - Travel -- Puerto Rico Slide Images, May 1974 (Box 64, Folder 10)
    - Travel -- Newport and Nantucket Slide Images, September 1974 (Box 64, Folder 11)
    - Travel -- Vieques Slide Images, December 1977 (Box 64, Folder 12)
    - Travel -- European Trip Notes Itineraries, March 1978 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Travel -- Holland, June 1978
      - Driving Permit, Medical Notes, Planning Notes (Box 29, Folder 5)
      - Slide Images, Driving Permit Photographs (Box 64, Folder 13)
    - Travel -- Israel Slide Images, January 1980 (Box 64, Folder 14)
    - Travel -- St. Barth's with Kathy Marx and Pat Mullen, January 1981
      - Planning Notes (Box 29, Folder 6)
      - Photographs, Slides, and Negatives (Box 64, Folder 15)
    - Travel -- Israel Slide Images, April 30-May 26, 1981 (Box 65, Folder 1)
    - Travel -- Jerusalem and Egypt, 1981, undated (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Travel -- St. Maarten Notes, Rental Agreements, Correspondence, 1981-1982 (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - Travel -- Paris Photographs, 1997 (Box 65, Folder 2)
    - Travel -- Paris Planning Notebook, May 18-31, 2002 (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - Travel -- Paris Planning Files, 2002; FA_MSS_642_ER_39
    - Travel -- Clothing and Medication Packing Lists, undated (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - Tuckahoe Lane House, circa 1960s-2000s
      - Photographs -- Back Yard, 1960s-1970s (Box 65, Folder 3)
      - Slide Images -- Exterior, Edie, Thea, October 1969 (Box 65, Folder 4)
      - Photographs and Slides -- Yard, Pool, Visitors, Edie's Mother, Edie Posing Nude, Thea, Spring-Summer 1970 (Box 65, Folder 5)
      - Photographs and Contact Sheets -- Friends, Parties, 1970s-1980s (Box 65, Folder 6)
      - Slide Images -- Exterior, Edie, Thea, May-October 1971 (Box 65, Folder 7)
      - Photographs -- Edie, Thea, Yard, May 1972 (Box 65, Folder 8)
      - Slide Images -- Exterior, Edie, Thea, 1974-1976 (Box 65, Folder 9)
      - Slide Images -- Yard and Pool Renovations, Tool House, Spring 1976 (Box 65, Folder 10)
      - Slide Images -- Yard and Pool, Interiors, Edie Posing, May-July 1976 (Box 65, Folder 11)
      - Slides and Photograph -- Yard, Visitors, Home Improvement, 1977 (Box 65, Folder 12)
      - Slide Images -- Visitors, Interior, Exterior, Spring 1978 (Box 65, Folder 13)
      - Photographs and Slides -- Thea, Edie, Visitors, House Renovations, Summer 1979 (Box 65, Folder 14)
      - Photographs -- Family Party, Visitors, Summer 1980 (Box 65, Folder 15)
      - Slide Images -- Edie's Family Visit, 1981 (Box 65, Folder 16)
      - Photographs -- Interior and Exteriors, 1981, undated (Box 65, Folder 17)
      - Slide Images -- Visitors, Parties, Wheelchair Delivery, Summer-Fall 1982 (Box 65, Folder 18)
      - Slide Images -- Visitors, Edie, Thea, Summer 1983 (Box 65, Folder 19)
      - Slide Images -- Playwright's Day Party, 1984 (Box 65, Folder 20)
      - Photographs -- Roof Replacement, May 1985 (Box 65, Folder 21)
      - Slide Images -- Post-Hurricane Damage, September/October 1985 (Box 65, Folder 22)
      - Slide Images -- Guests, Edie, Thea, October 1985 (Box 65, Folder 23)
      - Slide Images -- Yard, Edie, 1986 (Box 66, Folder 1)
      - Photographs -- Exterior and Yard, circa 1990s-2000s (Box 66, Folder 2)
      - Photographs -- Edie and Thea At Pool with Guests, 1990 (Box 66, Folder 3)
      - Photographs and Negatives -- Hurricane Damage, 1991 (Box 66, Folder 4)
      - Photographs and Negatives -- Edie, Thea, Guests, Yard and Interior Renovations, June-August 1992 (Box 66, Folder 5)
      - Photographs -- Family Visit, Yard, Summer 1993 (Box 66, Folder 6)
      - Photographs -- Edie's Bedroom and Basement Renovation, 1997, undated (Box 66, Folder 7)
      - Photographs -- Thea and Suki at the Pool, circa 2000-2007 (Box 66, Folder 8)
      - Photographs -- Edie and Thea in the Pool, August 2008 (Box 66, Folder 9)
      - Tax Assessment, 2006 (Box 28, Folder 20)
      - Licensing Agreement of Property, 2016 (Box 28, Folder 21)
    - Visit to Anne MacKay's Home -- Photographs, Summer 1992 (Box 66, Folder 10)
    - Visit to Friends at Meadowlark -- Slide Images, Summer 1979 (Box 66, Folder 11)
    - Washington Square Park Photographs, Spring 1981 (Box 66, Folder 12)
    - Wedding -- Planning Notebook, circa 2006-2007 (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - Wedding -- Planning Documentation, Correspondence, Vows, 2007; FA_MSS_642_ER_40
    - Wedding -- Harvey Brownstone Correspondence, Ceremony Planning, 2007 (Box 29, Folder 12-13)
    - Wedding -- License and Other Documentation, 2007 (Box 29, Folder 14)
    - Wedding -- Images of Toronto, Canada Travel and Ceremony, 2007
      - Photographs (Box 66, Folder 13)
      - Digital Images, FA_MSS_642_ER_2
      - Digital Video Recording of Ceremony, FA_MSS_642_ER_23
    - Wedding -- New York Times Marriage Announcement, May 27, 2007
      - Drafts, Final Version (Box 29, Folder 15)
      - Photograph Shoot Images and Negatives (Box 66, Folder 14)
    - Yom Kippur Dinner Party -- Photographs, 1986 (Box 66, Folder 15)
- Series II. Professional, 1950-2010; 4 Linear Feet in 6 manuscript boxes and 1 oversize flat box
  This series contains materials related to the professional lives of Edie Windsor, a computer programmer, and Thea Spyer, a clinical psychologist. Windsor worked primarily at IBM, beginning in the late 1950s, a period when computing was a predominantly male field, and then later ran her own consulting business in the 1980s. Spyer maintained a private practice for most of her career, up until her death in 2009, also working within a profession where women were underrepresented at the time. Materials include professional correspondence, published papers, records from professional organizations, and resumes. These materials reflect their careers and the professional environments they navigated.
  This series is arranged into two subseries:
  Subseries II.A. Edie Windsor
  Subseries II.B. Thea Spyer
  - Subseries II.A. Edie Windsor, 1950-2010; 3.45 Linear Feet in 6 manuscript boxes and 1 oversized flat box.
    This subseries documents Edie Windsor's professional career as a computer programmer, beginning in the late 1950s, at a time when the field was predominantly male. Due to her rarity in the field, Windsor was frequently highlighted in IBM's promotional materials and newsletters as a visible example of a woman succeeding in computing. Windsor was also actively involved in professional programming and personal computer communities throughout her career.
    Her academic foundation in the field is documented through her college papers and 1957 master's thesis from New York University. Her work as a technical manager at IBM from the late 1950s through the 1970s and then again in the mid-1980s is represented through memos, performance appraisals, and photographs. Windsor's participation in professional organizations is also well documented in this subseries through planning documents, publications, correspondence, and membership applications related to the International Dbase Users Group (IDBUG). In the 1980s, as personal computing became more widespread, Windsor became a founding member of the Board of Directors for the New York PC Users Group (NYPC), serving in various roles through the years. NYPC materials in this subseries include meeting minutes, reports, correspondence, and newsletters. Programs and notes from professional conferences are in this subseries, and of note is material from the 1987 National Computer Conference.
    This subseries also contains records from Windsor's consulting company, PC Classics, Inc., founded in 1985. Materials include promotional brochures, programming code, correspondence, and client files. Notably, Windsor worked with several LGBTQ+ organizations to help improve their technology practices, particularly in managing mailing lists. Under PC Classics, she also developed her own accounting software for personal computers, known as Windsor's Disburse Program. Documentation for this program includes a user manual, order form, and program disk.
    Windsor's prominence in the computing world is reflected in her media coverage, within 1984 articles in New York Magazine and Psychology Today, along with accompanying photographs. Additional materials include her resumes, business cards, and letterhead spanning from the late 1950s through the 1990s.
    - APL Language for IBM Personal Computer Documentation, 1983-1986 (Box 30, Folder 1-2)
    - Articles and Press Clippings -- PC Magazine, September 1983 (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Articles and Press Clippings -- New York Magazine and Psychology Today, January and September 1984
      - Articles on Home Computers Featuring Edie (Box 30, Folder 4)
      - Photographs for Articles (Box 66, Folder 16)
    - Business Cards, circa 1958-2009 (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Computer Conferences and Workshops -- General, 1979-1991 (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - Computer Conferences and Workshops -- The National Computer Conference, Chicago, June 15-18, 1987
      - Program, Notes (Box 30, Folder 7)
      - Photographs (Box 66, Folder 17)
    - Computer Conferences and Workshops -- Microsoft Database Technical Summit, August 26-29, 1992 (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence on AJAX Routine, 1957-1958 (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - Dick Bard -- Correspondence, Source Code Sheets, 1996, 2005, undated (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - DIF Programming Research and Documentation, 1981-1984 (Box 30, Folder 11)
    - Dissertation (NYU) -- Iterative Solutions of Biharmonic Difference... and related Correspondence, 1957-1977 (Box 30, Folder 12)
    - Employment Applications, Letters, Timecards, 1950-2010 (Box 31, Folder 1-3)
    - IBM Appraisal Forms, Letters, Brochure with Windsor's Image, 1960-1964 (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - IBM Newsletter IBM News, December 16, 1965 (Box 73, Folder 9)
    - IBM Photographs of Edie Working, 1965-1973 (Box 66, Folder 18)
    - IBM Photographs of Offices, circa 1987-1989 (Box 66, Folder 19)
    - IBM Correspondence, 1988, 2005-2007 (Box 31, Folder 5-6)
    - IDBUG (The International Dbase Users Group) -- Plans, Journal Publication, Letters, Application Forms, 1988-1990 (Box 31, Folder 7-9)
    - IDBUG (The International Dbase Users Group) -- XIDBUG Advisory Group, 1995 (Box 31, Folder 10)
    - New York PC Users Group (NYPC) -- Reports, Correspondence, Newsletters, Board Minutes, 1982-1988 (Box 31, Folder 11-14)
    - Paper -- Toward a Technology for Evaluation, September 1963 (Box 31, Folder 15)
    - Paper -- Coding for Performance Writing Outline, undated (Box 31, Folder 16)
    - PC Classics, Inc. -- Client Material -- First Editions Wallcoverings and Fabrics, Inc., 1980 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - PC Classics, Inc. -- Client Material -- Lesbian and Gay Community Services Center, Inc., 1984-1987 (Box 32, Folder 2-6, Box 73, Folder 10-11)
    - PC Classics, Inc. -- Source Code Related to Bonds, 1984 (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - PC Classics, Inc. -- Database System Forms for Law Office, circa 1985 (Box 32, Folder 8)
    - PC Classics, Inc. -- Windsor's Disburse Program User Guide, Order Form, 1985 (Box 32, Folder 9)
    - PC Classics, Inc. -- Correspondence, Forms, Source Code, PC-Outline Information, 1986-1992 (Box 32, Folder 10-11)
    - PC Classics, Inc. -- Completed Consultant Questionnaire and Related, 1988 (Box 32, Folder 12)
    - PC Classics, Inc. -- Client Material -- Bogue Electronic Manufacturing Co., 1988-1989 (Box 33, Folder 1-3)
    - PC Classics, Inc. -- Correspondence and Biographical Sketch, 1989 (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - PC Classics, Inc. -- Client Material -- Materials for the Arts, Proposal, 1990-1991 (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - PC Classics, Inc. -- Rate Schedule, circa 1980s-1990s (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - PC Classics, Inc. -- Programming Notes and Documentation for Swim Team, circa 1980s-1990s (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - Presentation Notes on Standards, February 3, 1964 (Box 33, Folder 8)
    - Resumes and Notes, 1950-2008 (Box 33, Folder 9-10)
    - Source Code for Programs, Notes, 1969-1996 (Box 33, Folder 11-15, Box 34, Folder 1-9)
    - Univac Printer Program Message Created by Windsor, circa 1950s (Box 34, Folder 10)
    - Xbase Language Standard Committee Reports and Meeting Notes, 1992-1993 (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - Subseries II.B. Thea Spyer, 1960-2009; 1 Linear Feet in 2 manuscript boxes.
    This subseries contains materials documenting the career of clinical psychologist Thea Spyer, who began practicing in institutional settings in the 1960s before establishing a private practice, which she maintained until her death in 2009. Her 1962 Ph.D. dissertation, along with professional journal articles from the 1970s, reflect her academic background and continued contributions to the field.
    Materials from her work at the Institute for the Crippled and Disabled (now The International Center for the Disabled) date from the 1960s and include brochures, letterhead, newsletters, photographs, and employee evaluations, providing insight into her early career and professional environment. The subseries also includes resumes and business cards from various stages of her career, documenting her sustained involvement in clinical psychology over several decades.
    - Article -- Therapy of Multiple Personality, 1971 (Box 34, Folder 12)
    - Article -- Ethical Problems and Some Guidelines, 1972 (Box 34, Folder 13)
    - Business Cards and Stationary, circa 1960s-2009 (Box 34, Folder 14)
    - Institute for the Crippled and Disabled, 1963-1967
      - Brochures, Letterhead, Newsletters, Work Evaluations (Box 34, Folder 15)
      - Photograph of Thea and Co-Workers (Box 66, Folder 20)
    - Ph.D. Dissertation -- Test Retest Stability of Rorschach…, October 1962 (Box 34, Folder 16)
    - Resumes, 1960s-1970s (Box 34, Folder 17)
- Series III. Activism, 1969-2024; 20.50 Linear Feet in 28 manuscript boxes, 2 small flat boxes, 3 oversize flat boxes, and 3 flat-file folders; 1,080 Megabytes in 718 computer files
  This series contains materials documenting the involvement of Edie Windsor, Thea Spyer, and later on Windsor's second wife, Judith Kasen-Windsor, in various LGBTQ+ organizations based in the New York City and Long Island areas. Their participation is reflected through records related to events, volunteer activities, and community engagement. The series also includes Windsor's files related to the 2013 Supreme Court case United States v. Windsor, in which she successfully challenged Section 3 of the Defense of Marriage Act (DOMA). The case resulted in the extension of federal rights and benefits to legally married same-sex couples.
  Subseries III.A. Events and Appearances
  Subseries III.B. Organizations
  Subseries III.C. United States v. Windsor
  - Subseries III.A. Events and Appearances, 1969, 1981-2022; 12 Linear Feet in 16 manuscript boxes, 4 oversized flat boxes, and 2 flat-file folders.; 834.34 Megabytes in 432 computer files